VAIBHAV SAHU

+1 (435)-553-9149, vaibhav.sahu@aggiemail.usu.edu, 1134 E 500 S, Salt Lake City, UT https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaibhavsahu, https://github.com/vaibhavsahu

A detail arianted and handwarding preferring with F. Congress of words are in large scale distributed protons

A detail-oriented and hardworking professional with 5+ years of work experience in large-scale distributed systems with focus on Java and Relational Databases with strong understanding of Algorithms, OOP and Data Structures.

EDUCATION:

Master of Science in Computer ScienceGPA – 3.7Utah State University, Logan, UTAug 2018Bachelor of Engineering in Computer ScienceGPA – 3.5Jabalpur Engineering College, Jabalpur IndiaJune 2010

METHODOLOGIES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Languages: Java/J2EE, Python [5+ years]
- Frameworks: Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Maven, JSP & Servlets, AngularJS, REST, JDBC, Maven, Junit, JMS
- Databases: Oracle 9i (SQL, PL/SQL) [3 years], My-SQL, MongoDB
- Tools and IDEs: SVN, JIRA, GitHub, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Docker, XCode, log4j, ActiveMQ, Jenkins, BitBucket
- Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, Solaris, Windows, and Mac
- Certifications: Sun Certified Java Programmer, IBM DB2 associate

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Python Developer, Utah State University

Project: Identifying Criticality in Market Sentiment: A Data Mining Approach

Aug 2016 - May 2018

- Developed tools to scrap Google, and Twitter for Oil, Gold, and S&P related information available on Internet
- Used Kolmogorov Complexity to measure the information
- Used Python and its scientific stack for data acquisition, analysis and visualization of the market sentiment

Java Developer, HCL Technologies, India

Apr 2014- Mar 2015

Project: Banking Service

- Involved in building GUI using JSF, JSP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Used MVC architecture framework like Struts to implement user interfaces. Implemented validations and tiles for web pages using struts validation framework
- Implemented User interface using Struts framework tag library JSP's and validation by using JavaScript
- Actively Involved in EJB component development, deployment for the different application interfaces
- Involved into writing and modifying the database stored procedures, functions and PL/SQL Scripts

Java Developer, Unisys, India

Dec 2010 - Mar 2014

Project: Logistics Management System

- Designed various tables required for the project in Oracle 9i database
- Extensively involved in programming the SQL Queries, Stored Procedures and Triggers in the application
- Modelled databases and created hibernate configuration files for mapping java beans (POJO) into database
- Designed, developed and maintained the data layer using JDBC and performed configuration of java application
- Created a user Interface through HTML and JSP, Standard Tag library
- Developed java beans and used Spring Core to implement the business logic

ACADEMIC PROJECTS:

Identification of Road Sign Boards Using OpenCV and TensorFlow

Aug 2016 – Dec 2016

- Developed an application that accepts a video as an input and scans for sign boards, and convert it to speech
- Python packages used: OpenCV, PyGame, Pickle, PyLab, TensorFlow

Twitter Sentiment Analysis for Six Major Airlines

Aug 2016 – Dec 2016

• Implemented a Naive Bayes classifier and performed an in-depth analysis of the raw data using classification and regression algorithms using Tableau, Open Refine and python